<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: UnitsKit | Steve Moser]]></title>
  <link href="http://stevemoser.github.io/blog/categories/unitskit/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://stevemoser.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-23T18:59:33-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://stevemoser.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steve Moser]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Falsehoods Programmers Believe About Systems of Measurement]]></title>
    <link href="http://stevemoser.github.io/blog/2013/08/07/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-systems-of-measurement/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-07T10:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://stevemoser.github.io/blog/2013/08/07/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-systems-of-measurement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When starting <a href="https://github.com/stevemoser/UnitsKit">UnitsKit</a> I had many false assumptions about how irregular systems of measurement could be.  Even after studying the subject and other existing libraries I was surprised by how many more irregularities I found. So inspired by Patrick McKenzie's post about <a href="http://www.kalzumeus.com/2010/06/17/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-names/">'Falsehoods Programmers Believe About Names'</a> I have set out to form a noncompelete list of irregulars when working with systems of measurement and converting between them.</p>

<ol>
<li>There is more than one variant of the metric system. (MKS vs CGS)</li>
<li>All base SI units are prefix-less. (The kilogram is the base unit of mass)</li>
<li>All derived metric units are derived of base SI units. (The liter is based off of decimeters)</li>
<li>Heterogenous units are of no practical use. (Radar beam height formula uses a constant expressed in nautical miles per foot)</li>
<li>Fractional dimensions are of no practical use. (Radar beam height formula uses a constant expressed in nautical miles per foot<sup>(1/2))</sup> (http://www.boost.org/doc/libs/1_37_0/doc/html/boost_units/Units.html)</li>
<li>Non-metric systems have base units as well.</li>
<li>Just as liters has decimeters so that it doesn't need a numerical proportionality constant, pints has BLANK. (I made up my own unit for this, a little more than 11 of them fit in a yard).</li>
<li>A gallon is treated much like a liter in their respective systems of measure. (Liter is not an official SI unit but a gallon is an official Imperial unit).</li>
<li>All base units are made of base dimensions. (The gallon 'base' unit made of the derived volume dimension)</li>
<li>A gallon is a gallon is a gallon. (Did you mean a liquid or dry gallon, US or Imperial, or a ten-gallon hat?)</li>
<li>Even written out unit names are case-sensitive (Calorie vs. calorie)</li>
<li>Base units always reduce to the same derived units. (Did you mean a Joule or a Newton meter? You might know but then you have to keep track of plane and solid angle units.)</li>
<li>Written out base units should always be presented in the same order (Are capital symbols, units with positive exponents, or length dimension units first?)</li>
<li>There is no need to differentiate between absolute and relative measurements. (Kelvin and Fahrenheit)</li>
<li>Derived unit symbols are represented the same way across systems of measure (mph vs km/h)</li>
<li>All units accepted for use with the SI are base ten (the hour and minute are base 60,Sexagesimal , blame the moon)</li>
<li>You will never have any namespace issues. (Is that h an hour or the Planck constant?</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
